A Guide to the Sara Teasdale Collection
University of Virginia Library
- LETTERS
  - Ruth Guthrie Harding, Paterson, New Jersey, to Sara Teasdale, 1913 Apr 11; ALS, 7 p. on 2 l. (Box Box 5)
    mentioning the [Alfred] Noyes affair and [Jessie Belle] Rittenhouse, sending her copy of
    for an inscription and praising its "Love-Songs," and discussing a reading by Alfred Noyes of
    The Forty Singing Seamen
  - Willard H. Wright, Editor, The Smart Set, New York, New York, to Sara Teasdale, St. Louis, Missouri, 1913 Apr 12; TLS, 1 p. (Box Box 5)
    admitting to be an admirer of her work and accepting "Enough" and "Prayer"
  - Eugene MacDonald Bonner, New York, New York, to Sara Teasdale, 1913 May 5; ALS, 1 p. (Box Box 5)
    requesting permission to set "Pierrot Plays in the Garden" to music
  - William Marion Reedy, Editor, The Mirror, St. Louis, Missouri, to Sara Teasdale, 1913 May 9; ALS, 1 p. (Box Box 5)
    commenting on her note and verse, "A Forsaken Garden" about the vandalism of Snows Garden
  - Louis Albert Lamb, to Sara Teasdale, 1913 May 17; ALS, 1 p. (Box Box 5)
    calling her poem, ["A Forsaken Garden"] "pure music in plainest English!..."
  - Helen S. Livingstone, Mineapolis, Minnesota, to Putnam Publishing Company, 1913 May 28; ALS, 2 p. on 1 l. (Box Box 5)
    requesting permission to publish a song, Sara Teasdale's "Pierrot," set to music
  - Vachel Lindsay, Springfield, Illinois, to Sara Teasdale, Altasand, Charlevoix, Michigan, 1913 July 11; ALS, 2 p. on 1 l., w/env. (Box Box 5)
    sending under separate cover
    The Creed of a Beggar
    The Rules of the Road
    , and looking forward to "a most profitable friendship"
  - Agnes Freer, Chicago, Illinois, to Sara Teasdale, 1913 July 19; ALS, 3 p. on 1 l. (Box Box 5)
    thanking her for the book of verse,
    , and praising her true touch
  - William Rose Benet, Editor, The Century Magazine, Union Square, New York, to Sara Teasdale, 1913 July 29; ALS, 1 p. (Box Box 5)
    praising one of her narrative poems and hoping to be able to publish it
  - Willard H. Wright, Editor, The Smart Set, New York, New York, to Sara Teasdale, St. Louis, Missouri, 1913 Aug 2; TLS, 1 p. (Box Box 5)
    holding two of her poems, "After Parting" and "February"
  - Henry Mills Alden, Editor, Harper's Magazine, New York, New York, to Sara Teasdale, St. Louis, Missouri, 1913 Aug 7; TLS, 1 p. (Box Box 5)
    discussing the poet's adaptation of his or her work to their wants
  - Alice C. Henderson, Poetry: A Magazine of Verse, to Sara Teasdale, 1913 Aug 16; ALS, 2 p. on 1 l. (Box Box 5)
    promising to take Sara Teasdale's book of poems to a nice quiet spot
  - Sidney Hosmer, Lake George, New York, to Sara Teasdale, St. Louis, Missouri, 1913 Aug 19; ALS, 2 p. on 1 l. (Box Box 5)
    thanking her for her book,
  - M. S. O'Donnell, Malden Marr, to Sara Teasdale, 1913 Aug 21; ALS, 1 p. (Box Box 5)
    requesting a signed autograph copy of her poem, "I Shall not Care"
  - Robert Sterling Yard, Editor, The Century Magazine, Union Square, New York, to Sara Teasdale, St. Louis, Missouri, 1913 Aug 26; TLS, 1 p. (Box Box 5)
    praising her "The Carpenter's Son" as a beautiful and impressive poem and accepting it for their Christmas issue
  - Charles Gallup, New York, New York, to Sara Teasdale, 1913 Sep 8; ALS, 1 p. (Box Box 5)
    requesting an autograph quotation and signature
  - Editor, The North American Review, New York, New York, to Sara Teasdale, St. Louis, Missouri, 1913 Sep 9; TLS, 1 p. (Box Box 5)
    accepting "Spring Night" for publication and requesting biographical information
  - Arthur B. Maurice, Editor, The Bookman, New York, New York, to Sara Teasdale, St. Louis, Missouri, 1913 Oct 2; TLS, 1 p. (Box Box 5)
    accepting "Sea Spray" at the usual rate
  - Willard H. Wright, Editor, The Smart Set, New York, New York, to Sara Teasdale, Hotel Martha Washington, New York, New York, 1913 Oct 11; TLS, 1 p. (Box Box 5)
    holding two of her poems, "Spring Night" and "The Subway Station," with a discussion of his thoughts on the latter
  - Willard H. Wright, Editor, The Smart Set, New York, New York, to Sara Teasdale, Hotel Martha Washington, New York, New York, 1913 Nov 15; TLS, 1 p. (Box Box 5)
    accepting "Heinkehr"
  - Frederick M. Steele, President, Standard Forgings Company, Chicago, Illinois, to Sara Teasdale, 1913 Nov 17; TLS, 1 p. (Box Box 5)
    requesting an autograph poem and signature to add to his "collection of autographic documents" in American literature
  - Elizabeth Cutting, The North American Review, New York, New York, to Sara Teasdale, 1913 Nov 21; ALS, 3 p. on 1 l. (Box Box 5)
    expressing her regrets at missing her visit and explaining their custom concerning payment when using a manuscript
  - Irwin L. Wheeler, New York, New York, to Sara Teasdale, 1913 Nov 26; ALS, 3 p. on 1 l. (Box Box 5)
    praising her work
  - Magda Decker, Webster Groves, Missouri, to Sara Teasdale, Hotel Martha Washington, New York, New York, 1913 Dec 8; ALS, 4 p. on 1 l., w/env. (Box Box 5)
    inviting her to read her poetry at the Monday Club's Poets Day, and mentioning Zoe Akins
  - William Stanley Braithwaite, Cambridge, Massachusetts, to Sara Teasdale, Hotel Martha Washington, New York, New York, 1913 Dec 9; ALS, 3 p. on 1 l. (Box Box 5)
    discussing his
    Anthology of Magazine Verse
    , requesting her to obtain permission from Robert Bridges to use her "Sappho" in the publication, and praising her verse
  - William Stanley Braithwaite, Cambridge, Massachusetts, to Sara Teasdale, 1913 Dec 30; ALS, 1 p. (Box Box 5)
    requesting a portrait and autograph copies of her poems "Sappho" and "The Old Maid" for promotional purposes
  - Sara Teasdale, New York, New York, to Bruce M. Stanley, Tucson, Arizona, 1913 Dec 30; APCS (Box Box 5)
  - Charles E. Howson, Brooklyn, New York, to Sara Teasdale, 1914 Jan 4; ALS, 2 p. on 1 l. (Box Box 5)
    asking her consent to set her poem, "Enough" to music
  - Williamina Parrish, Rome, Italy, to Vine Colby McCasland, Springfield, Missouri, 1914 Jan 6; APCS (Box Box 5)
  - Martha Foote Crow, Tuckahoe, New York, to Sara Teasdale, 1914 Jan 21; ALS, 3 p. on 1 l., w/enclosure (Box Box 5)
    hoping to see her at the Literature Committee meeting the following day, and mentioning John Hall Wheelock
  - Charles [ ], New York, New York, to Sara Teasdale, 1914 Jan 24; ALS, 2 p. on 1 l. (Box Box 5)
    discussing her poetry
  - Isabel Underhill, New York, New York, to Sara Teasdale, 1914 Jan 28; ALS, 2 p. on 1 l. (Box Box 5)
    requesting permission to set to music her poem, "The Lines"
  - Julia Ditto Young, Poets' House, Buffalo, New York, to [Sara Teasdale], 1914 Feb 5; TLS, 2 p. on 1 l., w/enclosure (Box Box 5)
    expressing appreciation of hearing several of Sara Teasdale's poems
  - Editor, Lippincott's Monthly Magazine, Philadelphia, Pennsylvania, to Sara Teasdale, St. Louis, Missouri, 1914 Feb 9; TLS, (Box Box 5)
    accepting her poems, "The Bay of Naples," "Alchemy," and "Twilight," w/ANS from Margaret Elizabeth Willard Teasdale on verso
  - Haviland Wessells, Peekskill, New York, to Sara Teasdale, 1914 Mar 5; ALS, 2 p. on 1 l. (Box Box 5)
    requesting to use "The Look" in a musical setting
  - Ines Macaulay, New York, New York, to Sara Teasdale, 1914 Mar 8; ALS, 4 p. on 1 l. (Box Box 5)
    and praising her work
  - Clifton B. Bull, Jr., Yonkers, New York, to Sara Teasdale, 1914 Mar 13; ALS, 3 p. on 1 l. (Box Box 5)
    requesting permission to publish her poem, "Song," with a musical setting
  - Sara Teasdale, St. Louis, Missouri, to Bruce M. Stanley, Tucson, Arizona, 1914 Mar 17; ALS, 2 p. on 1 l., w/env. (Box Box 5)
    expressing concern over Marion Cummings Stanley
  - Mme. Van Norman, Le Lyceum, New York, New York, to Sara Teasdale, 1914 Apr 8; ALS, 1 p. (Box Box 5)
    asking for an autographed volume of her work with a dedication for an exhibit
  - Hortense Flexner, Louisville, Kentucky, to Sara Teasdale, 1914 Apr 23; ALS, 2 p. on 1 l. (Box Box 5)
    praising her ability to write about certain subjects with such ease
  - Anita Bartle Brackenbury, Surrey, England, to Sara Teasdale, 1914 May 5; ALS, 4 p. on 4 l. (Box Box 5)
    expressing pleasure in her
    and naming several of her favorites, and mentioning poets she likes, such as Emily Dickinson, Josephine Preston Peabody, John Banister Tabb, and Bliss Carman
  - Elizabeth Cutting, The North American Review, New York, New York, to Sara Teasdale, St. Louis, Missouri, 1914 May 6; TLS, 1 p. (Box Box 5)
    accepting her poem, "To the Mother Of A Poet"
  - Elizabeth van R. Lemont, Wellesley, Massachusetts, to Sara Teasdale, 1914 May 23; ALS, 3 p. on 1 l. (Box Box 5)
    requesting permission to use her poem, "The Look," with a musical setting in the annual book of Songs by Wellesley Students
  - Percy Lee Atherton, Boston, Massachusetts, to Sara Teasdale, 1914 May 27; ALS, 1 p., w/enclosure (Box Box 5)
    requesting permission to set her poem, "The Look," to music
  - Florence H. Perin, Brookline, Massachusetts, 1914 June 1; TLS, 2 p. on 1 l. (Box Box 5)
    requesting one or more of Sara Teasdale's poems to be included in her compilation books of poems and prayers, "Sunlit Days" and "Starlit Nights"
  - Louise Ayres Garnett, Evanston, Illinois, to Sara Teasdale, 1914 June 5; ALS, 3 p. on 1 l. (Box Box 5)
    thanking her for permission to set her poem, "The Look," to music and mentioning Eunice Tietjens
  - Editor, The Bookman, to Sara Teasdale, St. Louis, Missouri, 1914 June 25; TL, 1 p. (Box Box 5)
    enclosing a check for use of her poem, "At Night," in their July issue
  - Elsie Jade Hawson, Fresno, California, to Sara Teasdale, 1914 July 6; ALS, 2 p. on 1 l. (Box Box 5)
    requesting permission to use her poem, "The Look," for a musical setting
  - Edward J. Wheeler, Editor, Current Opinion, to Sara Teasdale, Charlevoix, Michigan, 1914 Aug 19; TLS, 2 p. on 2 l. (Box Box 5)
    praising and critiquing her
    Rivers to the Sea
  - Charles E. Rush, Librarian, The Free Public Library of St. Joseph, Missouri, to Sara Teasdale, St. Louis, Missouri, 1914 Oct 14; TLS, 2 p. on 2 l. (Box Box 5)
    asking for her "hearty approval" and help with their `House Party' honoring Missouri authors and writers, and describing the city's and the library's plans for the affair
  - Charles Hanson Towne, along with Edith M. Thomas and Percy MacKaye, New York, New York, to Sara Teasdale, 1914 Nov 10; TL, 1 p. (Box Box 5)
    requesting Sara Teasdale's presence at a dinner in honor of Jessie Belle Rittenhouse as one of those represented in Rittenhouse's volume,
    The Little Book of Modern American Verse
  - Allen Dale Smith, Jr., Galveston, Texas, to Sara Teasdale, 1914 Dec 4; ALS, 2 p. on 1 l. (Box Box 5)
    asking who published
    Sonnets to Duse
    and whether or not she has had published subsequent volumes
  - Clara K. Wellman, Cleveland, Ohio, to Sara Teasdale, 1915 Jan 4; ALS, 2 p. on 1 l. (Box Box 5)
    requesting permission to publish "The Look," as a song
  - Mary Blue, Dayton, Ohio, to Sara Teasdale, St. Louis, Missouri, 1915 Jan 7; ALS, 2 p. on 1 l. (Box Box 5)
    requesting permission to publish her poem, "The Look," as a song, and explaining that she is seventeen and wishes to further her education as a pianist
  - Paul A. Schmitt, Minneapolis, Minnesota, to Sara Teasdale, St. Louis, Missouri, 1915 Jan 25; TLS, 1 p. (Box Box 5)
    requesting on behalf of the composer permission to publish her poem, "The Look," with a musical setting
  - Sara Teasdale Filsinger, Arthur Hotel, St. Louis, Missouri, to Frank George, 1915 Feb 13; ALS, 3 p. on 1 l. (Box Box 6)
    claiming that his daughter Barbara George's poems are charming, and giving news of her marriage to Ernst B. Filsinger on December 19
  - Howes Norris, Jr., Vineyard Haven, Massachusetts, to Sara Teasdale, 1915 Feb 19; ALS, 1 p. (Box Box 6)
    requesting some sentiment and autograph for his collection
  - H. L. Mencken, Editor, Smart Set, to Sara Teasdale, St. Louis, Missouri, 1915 Feb 23; TLS, 1 p., w/env. (Box Box 6)
    accepting her poems "Swan" and "Come" for publication, and mentioning "Dusk in War-Time," "Morning," "Leaves," and "Bitterness"
  - Edward L. B. Howard, Boston, Massachusetts, to Sara Teasdale Filsinger, St. Louis, Missouri, 1915 Mar 5; ALS, 2 p. on 1 l., w/env. (Box Box 6)
    requesting her autograph for his collection of over two-hundred poets
  - William Rose Benet, Assistant Editor, The Century Magazine, to Sara Teasdale Filsinger, St. Louis, Missouri, 1915 Mar 8; TLS, 1 p. (Box Box 6)
    accepting her poems "Peace" and "The Lighted Window" for publication, w/ANS at bottom
  - Douglas Malloch, The Society of Midland Authors, Chicago, Illinois, to Sara Teasdale Filsinger, St. Louis, Missouri, 1915 Mar 11; TLS, 1 p., w/env. (Box Box 6)
    requesting her membership in their new organization
  - Charlotte V. Butterfield, Saybrook, Connecticut, to Sara Teasdale Filsinger, St. Louis, Missouri, 1915 Mar 16; ANS, 2 p. on 1 l., w/env. (Box Box 6)
    requesting permission to publish her poem "The Look" to a musical setting
  - The Survey, New York, New York, to Sara Teasdale Filsinger, Arthur Hotel, St. Louis, Missouri, 1915 Mar 19; TLS, 1 p., w/env. (Box Box 6)
    requesting permission to publish her poem "Spring" with the understanding that they cannot pay
  - [ ], Department of English, Washington University, St. Louis, Missouri, to Sara Teasdale Filsinger, Arthur Hotel, St. Louis, Missouri, 1915 Mar 23; ALS, 1 p., w/env. (Box Box 6)
    extending an invitation to her and her husband to see him and his class on April 1, and briefly discussing his plans for that day's class
  - Carl Hahn, Musical Director, New York, New York, to Editor, Scribner's Magazine, 1915 Mar 24; TLS, 1 p., w/env. (Box Box 6)
    requesting permission to publish Sara Teasdale's "The River" with music
  - The Denver Music Company, Denver, Colorado, to Sara Teasdale Filsinger, St. Louis, Missouri, 1915 Mar 26; TLS, 1 p., w/env. (Box Box 6)
    requesting permission to publish a musical setting of her poem "The Look"
  - Timothy Spelman, Brooklyn, New York, to Sara Teasdale Filsinger, Arthur Hotel, St. Louis, Missouri, 1915 Apr 24; ALS, 4 p. on 1 l., w/env. (Box Box 6)
    requesting permission to use three of her poems as lyrics for songs
  - Harper & Brothers, New York, New York, to Sara Teasdale Filsinger, Arthur Hotel, St. Louis, Missouri, 1915 May 5; TLS, 1 p., w/env. (Box Box 6)
    accepting her poem "The Cloud" for publication
  - Jacqueline Hendrick Hoyt, New York, New York, to Sara Teasdale Filsinger, Arthur Hotel, St. Louis, Missouri, 1915 May 12; ALS, 2 p. on 1 l., w/env. (Box Box 6)
    requesting permission to use several of her poems from
    for musical settings
  - Robert Frost, Littleton, New Hampshire, to Ernest B. Filsinger, St. Louis, Missouri, 1915 May 16; ALS, 1 p., w/env. (Box Box 6)
    thanking him for his generous praise, admiring his wife's poetry, and mentioning Louis Untermeyer
  - Edmund R. Brown, Boston, Massachusetts, to Sara Teasdale Filsinger, Arthur Hotel, St. Louis, Missouri, 1915 May 19; TLS, 2 p. on 1 l., w/env. (Box Box 6)
    concerning an idea of selling an autographed collection of books of verse and about verse to raise money for
    , and mentioning Conrad Aiken, Temple Scott, and William Stanley Braithwaite
  - H. L. Mencken, Editor, The Smart Set, to Sara Teasdale Filsinger, Arthur Hotel, St. Louis, Missouri, 1915 June 3; TLS, 1 p., w/env. (Box Box 6)
    accepting her poem "Dreams" for publication
  - Ella Wheeler Wilcox, Short Beach, Connecticut, to Sara Teasdale Filsinger, St. Louis, Missouri, 1915 June 14; TLS, 1 p., w/env. (Box Box 6)
    writing in appreciation of her charming note, and mentioning Theodosia (Garrison) Faulks
  - Amy M. Beach, San Francisco, California, to Sara Teasdale Filsinger, St. Louis, Missouri, 1915 June 17; ALS, 3 p. on 1 l., w/env. (Box Box 6)
    writing in appreciation of her kind note and enclosed lyrics, praising "Night Song at Amalfi" particularly, and wishing to compose songs from some of the poems whenever she is not too busy with giving concerts
  - Ernest R. Kroeger, Director, The Kroeger School of Music, St. Louis, Missouri, to Sara Teasdale Filsinger, St. Louis, Missouri, 1915 June 18; TLS, 1 p., w/env. (Box Box 6)
    expecting to set to music her poems "Come" and "The Kiss" this summer
  - Robert F. Walker, Judge, Supreme Court, Jefferson City, Missouri, to William Marion Reedy, Reedy's Mirror, St. Louis, Missouri, 1915 June 18; TLS, 1 p. (Box Box 6)
    criticizing Sara Teasdale's recently published "In a Lighted Window"
  - William Marion Reedy, Reedy's Mirror, St. Louis, Missouri, to Sara Teasdale Filsinger, St. Louis, Missouri, 1915 June 21; ALS, 2 p. on 2 l., w/env. (Box Box 6)
    discussing her little boy poem ["In a Lighted Window"] and Judge Walker's opinion of it in his June 18 letter, expressing his view of Zoe [Akin] and her anthology, and discussing free verse
  - Edward C. Murch, The MacMillan Company, New York, New York, to Sara Teasdale Filsinger, St. Louis, Missouri, 1915 July 1; TLS, 1 p., w/env. (Box Box 6)
    offering a royalty of ten percent on all copies sold of her
    and submitting a sample page
  - William Rose Benet, The Century Magazine, New York, New York, to Sara Teasdale Filsinger, St. Louis, Missouri, 1915 July 2; TLS, 1 p., w/env. (Box Box 6)
    accepting the revision of "Summer Night, Riverside" for future publication
  - Mr. and Mrs. John Warren Teasdale, Charlevoix, Michigan, to Sara Teasdale Filsinger, St. Louis, Missouri, 1915 July 3; Telegram (Box Box 6)
    congratulating her on her success with The MacMillan Company
  - Luella Ohusted Burnham, Wellesley, Massachusetts, to Sara Teasdale Filsinger, St. Louis, Missouri, 1915 July 8; ALS, 2 p. on 1 l., w/env. (Box Box 6)
    requesting permission to set to music her poem "The Look"
  - Martha Emma Watts, Asheville, North Carolina, to Sara Teasdale Filsinger, St. Louis, Missouri, 1915 July 18; ALS, 4 p. on 1 l., w/env. (Box Box 6)
    congratulating her on having her poems published by The MacMillan Company and telling of her own writing
  - G. Schirmer (Inc.), Music Publishers, New York, New York, to Sara Teasdale Filsinger, St. Louis, Missouri, 1915 July 23; TLS, 1 p., w/env. (Box Box 6)
    requesting to use two musical settings "But What if I Heard my First Love" and "The Kiss in Colin's Eye" based on her poems
  - The MacMillan Company, New York, New York, to Messrs. Stix, Baer, & Fuller, St. Louis, Missouri, 1915 July 23; TL, 1 p. (Box Box 6)
    concerning the publication of Sara Teasdale's poetry and the possibility of having advance order copies autographed
  - William Stanley Braithwaite, Cambridge, Massachusetts, to Sara Teasdale Filsinger, St. Louis, Missouri, 1915 July 27; ALS, 2 p. on 1 l., w/env. (Box Box 6)
    concerning his anthology coming out in October, and asking her assistance by sending her extra set of proofs when corrected and by contacting William Marion Reedy
  - John Alden Carpenter, Chicago, Illinois, to Sara Teasdale Filsinger, St. Louis, Missouri, 1915 July 28; ALS, 1 p., w/env. (Box Box 6)
    praising her poems that she sent and hoping to use some of them
  - William Marion Reedy, Reedy's Mirror, St. Louis, Missouri, to Sara Teasdale Filsinger, St. Louis, Missouri, 1915 July 28; TLS, 1 p., w/env. (Box Box 6)
    feeling that her book will be a success
  - Rosalie L. Hausmann, San Francisco, California, to Sara Teasdale Filsinger, Charlevoix, Michigan, 1915 Aug 12; ALS, 3 p. on 1 l., w/env. (Box Box 6)
    complimenting her poems as being admirably fitted for American songs, and saying that she has set four of them to musical settings
  - Conrad Aiken, Cuttingsville, Vermont, to Sara Teasdale Filsinger, Charlevoix, Michigan, 1915 Aug 14; ALS, 1 p., w/env. (Box Box 6)
    criticizing the Imagist movement but commenting favorably on John Gould Fletcher's work, and mentioning his drifting away from the group
  - Henry A. Bellows, The Bellman, Minneapolis, Minnesota, to Sara Teasdale Filsinger, [Charlevoix, Michigan], 1915 Aug 14; TLS, 1 p., w/env. (Box Box 6)
    accepting one of her poems for publication
  - W. J. Marsh, Fort Worth, Texas, to Sara Teasdale Filsinger, Charlevoix, Michigan, 1915 Aug 23; ALS, 2 p. on 2 l., w/env. (Box Box 6)
    concerning a suite of songs "Five Songs of Autumn" written by himself using her poems "Twilight," "November," "Dreams," and "Dead Leaves"
  - John G. Neihardt, Bancroft, Nebraska, to Sara Teasdale Filsinger, St. Louis, Missouri, 1915 Sep 14; ALS, 3 p. on 1 l., w/env. (Box Box 6)
    agreeing to see her book and review it, discussing the "woman and poet," mentioning MacMillan publishing his
    Song of Hugh Glass
    , and inquiring about her interest in Greek
  - O. W. Firkins, Minneapolis, Minnesota, to Sara Teasdale Filsinger, St. Louis, Missouri, 1915 Sep 19; ALS, 3 p. on 1 l., w/env. (Box Box 6)
    agreeing to review her book and giving a lengthy discussion of a reviewer's work
  - Maggie W. Barry, Sherman, Texas, to Sara Teasdale Filsinger, St. Louis, Missouri, 1915 Sep 19; ALS, 3 p. on 1 l., w/env. (Box Box 6)
    praising and criticizing her poetry, and discussing the teaching of poetry
  - Frederick Hoppin Nowland, Philadelphia, Pennsylvania, to Sara Teasdale Filsinger, St. Louis, Missouri, 1915 Sep 25; ALS, 2 p. on 1 l., w/env. (Box Box 6)
    requesting permission to quote her poem "Spring in War Time" in a book being prepared about the war in Europe
  - Gordon Balch Nevin, Cleveland, Ohio, to Sara Teasdale Filsinger, St. Louis, Missouri, 1915 Sep 28; TLS, 1 p., w/env. (Box Box 6)
    requesting permission to use her poem "I Shall Not Care" in a musical setting
  - Wilbur L. Cross, Editor, Yale Review, New Haven, Connecticut, to Sara Teasdale Filsinger, St. Louis, Missouri, 1915 Oct 1; TLS, 1 p., w/env. (Box Box 6)
    asking for some poems
  - John Hall Wheelock, Charles Scribner's Sons, New York, New York, to Sara Teasdale Filsinger, 1915 Oct 9; ALS, 8 p. on 4 l., w/env. (Box Box 6)
    giving glowing and detailed praise of her work in
    , writing of "the deep human beauty of this great poem," "the holy core of life itself...and needful to be reminded by such as you,--...," Sara Teasdale as "an unabashed lover of life," "this expression of the fundamental emotion in its elements..."
  - E. H. Anderson, Director, New York Public Library, to Sara Teasdale Filsinger, St. Louis, Missouri, 1915 Oct 12; TLS, 1 p., w/env. (Box Box 6)
    revealing that the Library system has copies of her book of poems,
  - O. W. Firkins, Minneapolis, Minnesota, to Sara Teasdale Filsinger, St. Louis, Missouri, 1915 Oct 15; ALS, 1 p., w/env. (Box Box 6)
    [Rivers to the Sea]
    , and promising a judgment
  - Grace L. Dawson, New York, New York, to Sara Teasdale Filsinger, St. Louis, Missouri, 1915 Oct 15; ALS, 4 p. on 2 l. (Box Box 6)
    writing in response to Sara's illness and mentioning her new book and some of her verse
  - Miles M. Dawson, New York, New York, to Sara Teasdale Filsinger, St. Louis, Missouri, 1915 Oct 15; ALS, 4 p. on 1 l., w/env. (Box Box 6)
    expressing his gratitude for her book and praising the verses
  - Rudolph Rieder, Madison, Wisconsin, to Sara Teasdale Filsinger, St. Louis, Missouri, 1915 Oct 15; ALS, 4 p. on 1 l. (Box Box 6)
    (written in German)
  - Underwood's News Photo Service, New York, New York, to Sara Teasdale Filsinger, St. Louis, Missouri, 1915 Oct 15; TLS, 1 p., w/env. (Box Box 6)
    replying to her letter concerning a full face or profile picture of her to use in their service
  - Rudolph Rieder, Madison, Wisconsin, to Sara Teasdale Filsinger, St. Louis, Missouri, 1915 Oct 16; ALS, 8 p. on 2 l., w/enclosures, w/env. (Box Box 6)
  - Ella Wheeler Wilcox, Short Beach, Connecticut, to Sara Teasdale Filsinger, St. Louis, Missouri, 1915 Oct 18; TLS, 1 p., w/env. (Box Box 6)
    expressing appreciation of her book
    and praising her verses